Joudi Abou Ayed

737 Campus Drive, 214, Stanford, CA 94305

+1 (650) 334-7081 :: JOUDIAA@STANFORD.EDU :: LINKEDIN.COM/JOUDIAA :: GITHUB.COM/JOUDIAA

Audio Engineer

Dedicated and experienced Audio Engineer with extensive knowledge of audio science and technology principles, theories, specifications, and standards as well as music proficiency and experience. Bringing leadership, passion, and experience to the table. Proven track record of working with complex audio concepts and diverse music projects, and taking the lead in project management and submitting ahead of schedule.

Skills

- DAWs: Protools, Logic Pro, Ableton Live, Studio One, and Harrison Mixbus
- Languages: Arabic, French, English, and Korean
- Exceptional written and verbal communication skills
- Leadership, Problem Solving, and Teamwork

Projects

- Cryptography: Enigma Simulator
- Web Design: Toot Ur Floot Twitter Simulator
- Game re-designs: Wordle, Breakout, Adventure, and Match the Flag
- Original Games and Audio
 Experiences: Sunday Nights,
 Squid Game Audio Visualizer,
 Violent Violin, Chuqahwa Arab
 Music Sequencer
 (Links on Gifflub).

Experience

Audio Research Assistant – 06/2022 to 12/2022 Stanford Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics, Stanford

 Software troubleshooting using Markdown, Javascript, and HTML of the department's equipment documentation online guides, as well as the department's hardware and software consistent maintenance.

Sound Engineer and Studio Manager– 06/2020 to 06/2021 **Music Yard Studios,** Cairo – Egypt

• Controlled and monitored sound reinforcement, electronic instruments, and amplifiers and manager studio schedule

Live Sound/Livestream Engineer – 09/2020 to 05/2021 The American University in Cairo, Cairo – Egypt

- Set up audio equipment for the music department concerts
- Monitored the audio mix throughout a performance or recording session to ensure that it is of high quality

Audio Technology Professor – 09/2020 to 06/2021 The American University in Cairo, Cairo – Egypt

• Prepared material for class lectures and taught hands-on audio mechanical engineering skills and principles

Sound Engineer/Intern– 06/2018 to 09/2018 **Audio Addicts Studio,** Beirut – Lebanon

 Recorded songs and VO for international artists (Banah's Shou Helou Nihna single)

Education

Stanford University / Masters of Music in Music, Science, and Technology (September 2021 – June 2023, Stanford)

The American University in Cairo (AUC) / Bachelor of Arts in Music Technology (September 2015 – June 2019, Cairo-Egypt)

The American University in Cairo (AUC) / Bachelor of Musical Arts in Music Performance (September 2015 – June 2019, Cairo-Egypt)

Awards

Valerie Farag Music Award at the AUC Centennial Ceremony, June 2019

Three American University in Cairo Presidential Certificates of Recognition for Outstanding Academic Achievement as a scholarship recipient, May 2017- May 2019